MIGUEL FERNANDES

+49152337014457 amgfernandes@gmail.com

NEUROSCIENTIST



LinkedIn//amgfernandes

SKILLS

PROFESSIONAL

Python

Machine learning

Neuroscience

Life Sciences

Hugo (Website)

PERSONAL

Communication

Teamwork

Adaptability

Problem solving

I am an experienced Neuroscientist fascinated by the *analysis of data* to extract *valuable insights* and *create knowledge*. I believe that knowledge and education empower people and improve our world. I love teaching and *working in a team* to solve complex questions.

Würmstraße. 11 Gräfelfing +49152337014457

Munich, Germany amgfernandes@gmail.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

NEUROSCIENTIST

2013-2020

I am using several methods, including high-resolution behavioral tracking, neuronal imaging, molecular and **machine learning approaches** to study behavioral choice in zebrafish.

PHD STUDENT

2009-2013

I worked on the development and functions of hypothalamic neurons using behavior, genetics and confocal imaging approaches. *Hans-Grisebach Award: Outstanding dissertation in the field of biochemistry and molecular biology*

EDUCATION

PHD BIOLOGY 2009-2013

University of Freiburg, Germany

MASTERS IN BIOLOGY 2003-2009

University of Porto, Portugal

REFERENCES

HERWIG BAIER WOLFGANG DRIEVER

Max Planck Director Professor

hbaier@neuro.mpg.de driever@biologie.uni-freiburg.de